{"quizCode":"Qc3223","quizName":"Marvel Cinematic Universe","numberOfQuestions":15,"questions":[{"question":"Who is the primary villain in the first 'Avengers' movie?","options":["Loki","Thanos","Ultron","Red Skull"],"answer":"Loki","explanation":"Loki is the primary villain in the first 'Avengers' movie.","difficulty":"Medium"},{"question":"What is the name of Tony Stark's personal AI assistant?","options":["JARVIS","FRIDAY","ULTRON","DUM-E"],"answer":"JARVIS","explanation":"JARVIS is the name of Tony Stark's personal AI assistant.","difficulty":"Easy"},{"question":"What is the name of the metal that Tony Stark's suit is made of?","options":["Adamantium","Vibranium","Palladium","Titanium"],"answer":"Titanium","explanation":"Tony Stark's suit is made of Titanium.","difficulty":"Easy"},{"question":"What is the name of the organization that Nick Fury leads?","options":["SHIELD","HYDRA","AIM","Alpha Flight"],"answer":"SHIELD","explanation":"Nick Fury leads SHIELD.","difficulty":"Medium"},{"question":"What is the name of the planet that Thor is from?","options":["Asgard","Vormir","Sakaar","Knowhere"],"answer":"Asgard","explanation":"Thor is from Asgard.","difficulty":"Easy"},{"question":"Who is the leader of the Chitauri army in the first 'Avengers' movie?","options":["Loki","Thanos","Ultron","The Other"],"answer":"The Other","explanation":"The leader of the Chitauri army in the first 'Avengers' movie is The Other.","difficulty":"Medium"},{"question":"What is the name of the organization that the Winter Soldier is associated with?","options":["Hydra","Aim","Shield","Leviathan"],"answer":"Hydra","explanation":"The Winter Soldier is associated with Hydra.","difficulty":"Medium"},{"question":"What is the name of the superpowered villain played by Michael Keaton in 'Spider-Man: Homecoming'?","options":["Green Goblin","Vulture","Doctor Octopus","Sandman"],"answer":"Vulture","explanation":"Michael Keaton played the superpowered villain Vulture in 'Spider-Man: Homecoming'.","difficulty":"Medium"},{"question":"What is the name of the giant green superhero played by Mark Ruffalo in the MCU?","options":["The Thing","The Hulk","Colossus","Juggernaut"],"answer":"The Hulk","explanation":"Mark Ruffalo played the giant green superhero The Hulk in the MCU.","difficulty":"Medium"},{"question":"What is the name of the team of superheroes led by Captain America?","options":["The Avengers","The Defenders","The X-Men","The Guardians of the Galaxy"],"answer":"The Avengers","explanation":"The team of superheroes led by Captain America is called The Avengers.","difficulty":"Medium"}]}
